We have a transfer student joining us today.
（教師）
今日は転校生が来ています
Go ahead and introduce yourself.
じゃあ 自己紹介して
I'm Asagiri Minori.
（浅桐(あさぎり)みのり）
浅桐みのりです
Asagiri
Minori
よろしく
Nice to meet you.
Mob Psycho
Discord
~Choices~
What? Your dad runs a company, Asagiri-san?
（女子生徒１）
えっ？　浅桐さんのお父さんって
社長なの？
That's awesome!
（女子生徒２）
すっごい！
Wanna come over sometime?
（みのり）今度 うち来る？
（女子生徒１）行く 行く！
Heck yeah!
Let's have a welcoming party.
（男子生徒１）
じゃあ 歓迎会やろうぜ！
（女子生徒２）
よっしゃ！
All right. Whoever's going,
write your name down.
（女子生徒１）
参加する人は名前 書いてって～
（男子生徒たち）
ヘ～イ！　はい～ 書く 書く！
I'm definitely writing my name down!
No need to bother asking Kageyama.
（男子生徒２）影山(かげやま)はいいだろ？
（男子生徒１）だよな
Yeah.
What's his deal? The token punching bag?
あの人 何なの？
いじられキャラ？
（女子生徒１）
さあ　何の印象もないかも
Who knows? I've never
really thought about him.
（女子生徒２）
存在感ゼロ
He's barely noticeable.
ふ～ん
Hope
Oh, I see...
そっか そっか
The people here are accurate representations
of actual people from the real world.
（最上(もがみ)啓示(けいじ)）
これらの登場人物は
全て実際にいる人間を
そのまま再現したものだ
So what you're experiencing is a parallel
world that could've easily come to pass
つまり 君は今
環境さえ違えば
こうなったかもしれないという―
had your circumstances
been slightly different.
パラレルワールドを体験している
そのうえで 超能力の使えない君を
観察させてもらおう
And I'll observe how you fare in this
environment without your powers.
Don't give me that "I don't know" crap!
（教師）
“分かりません”じゃねえよ！
Are my lessons that boring?
俺の授業 そんなに退屈か？
そのまま立ってろ
You can stay standing.
All that was left in the
problem was addition.
（男子生徒）
足し算しか残ってないのに…
Talk about lame.
（男子生徒たち）
かっこ悪(わる)っ　バカすぎる
He's too stupid.
Hey, stop that...
（男子生徒たち）
やめとけよ　あいつ 固まってるぜ
He's completely frozen.
You had plenty of relationships in real life,
（最上）
現実の君は縁に富んでいたが
and you were fortunate enough
to be surrounded by good people.
自分の周りは いい人ばかり…
そんな環境は ごくまれだ
Situations like that are extremely rare.
You don't have a phone or wallet on you,
and no parents at home?
（杉本(すぎもと)）
携帯も財布もねえし
親も いねえだと？
ふざけやがって
鼻の形 変えるぞ！
Don't give me that shit!
How about I give you a nose job?!
Please... let me go...
（モブ）
放してくださ…
（細川(ほそかわ)）
なんだ？　やんのか？
What? You wanna go?
（杉本）
おう 来いよ
Bring it!
Get 'im, Sugimoto!
（細川）
いけ！　杉本 いけ いけ！
Come on! Come on!
Where the hell are you looking?!
（杉本）
どこ見てんだ？　おら！
Your extremely talented brother is
no more than a stranger here.
（最上）
優秀な弟も ここでは他人だ
It looks like you refrain from using
your powers in your personal life.
君は私生活では“力”の使用を
控えているみたいだな
I'm guessing you're trying to
become a better person
より充実して生きるため
by focusing on developing your social skills
rather than your powers,
超能力よりも 要するに人間力を
身に着けたいという訳なんだろうが
but only the fortunate in life
would even have that idea.
いかにも恵まれた者の
考えそうなことだ
It shows how lightly you take the real world.
世の中を甘く見ている
If only I were stronger...
僕に もっと力があれば…
Nature
Dream
Friendship
Darkness
Nature
Here, have some milk!
はい 牛乳
あれ？
Wait, didn't you mention you loved milk?
確か“牛乳 好き”って
言ってなかったっけ？
Isn't this what you meant?
こういう意味じゃなかった？
Ew, you reek of milk.
ってか 牛乳くっさ
（教師）
チッ… 誰か あとで
雑巾かけておくように
One of you better mop that up.
I'm sure that this must
seem inexplicable to you,
（最上）
君からすれば不可解だろうが
このイジメ行為は
but she's bullying you in order
to secure her position in society,
彼女が自分のポジションを
確保するため
and it's something she's done routinely.
日常的にやってきたことだ
If you don't become stronger,
you'll be used, exploited,
強くならなければ
利用され 搾取され
and forever a stepping stone for others.
踏み台にされ続ける
Not looking good.
（エクボ）
ダメだ
こりゃ 茂夫(しげお) 負けたぞ
Pretty sure Shigeo lost.
But it hasn't even been thirty minutes yet.
（霊幻新隆(れいげんあらたか)）
まだ30分も経ってないだろう？
（エクボ）
かかりすぎだ！
That's way too long!
普通は１分もありゃ終わるもんだろ
He should've been done in a minute.
If this keeps up,
his sense of self will fall apart.
このままじゃ
あいつの自我は崩壊する
死ぬってことだ！
He's going to die!
Mob is someone who can
solve things on his own.
（霊幻）
モブは自分の力で解決できる男だ
He actually has strength, unlike me.
俺と違って
ちゃんと強い部分がある
Quit being naïve. The next time this
guy wakes up, we're all finished.
（エクボ）
甘(あめ)えよ
次にヤツが目覚めたら
今度こそ 皆殺しだ！
Anxiety, fear, rage...
（最上）
恐怖 不安 怒り
All the negative emotions are
collectively welling up within you.
総合的な負の感情が高まってきたな
That's only natural after living in this
world for six months without your powers.
超能力もなく
この世界で半年 過ごせば
当然の結果だ
You mustn't misuse your powers.
“力”の使い方を
間違えてはいけない
Calpas
Saga Building
I could see spirits ever since I was born.
私は生まれつき 霊が見えた
I even had the power to exorcise them.
それをはらう力も持っていた
At first, I used my powers for good,
最初は世のため人のため
by giving advice and
solving various problems.
いろいろな相談に乗り
解決してきた
The Psychic of the Century
Mogami Keiji-san
But my mother developed a mysterious illness,
母が原因不明の病にかかり
治療費がバカにならなかったんだ
and the fees for her treatment were obscene.
Eventually, I started taking underground
jobs to kill people for money.
やがて私は 黒いルートから
殺しの依頼を受けて
金を受け取るようになった
I even gave up sleep
to earn as much as I could.
私は寝る間を惜しんで金を稼いだ
But my mother still died.
しかし 母は死んだ
The cause of her illness
remained unclear to the end.
最後まで病の原因は分からず
なすすべがなかった
There was nothing anyone could do.
But then, I found out...
だが 私は知ってしまった
After her death, my mother
became an evil spirit and said...
死後 悪霊と化した母が…
（最上の母）
全部 お前のせいだ！
It's all your fault!
My own actions brought forth evil around me,
（最上）
私の行為が
自分の周りに“魔”を集め
and that's what ended up plaguing her.
その災いが
母に降りかかっていたのだ
I should've doubted my way of life,
how I was being used by others.
利用されて生きることに
疑問を持つべきだった
Suicide by Hanging
Early yesterday, Mogami Keiji-san,
the famous psychic, was discovered dead.
（アナウンサー）
昨日未明
霊能力者として知られている…
News
I became an evil spirit and decided to
use my powers for myself this time.
（最上）
私は悪霊と化し
According to the MPD, the
cause of death was suicide.
今度は自分の意思で
“力”を使うことを決めた
I was going to change the world.
世直しだ
I began to punish those who
brought misfortune to others.
私は 人に不幸を与える人間につき
制裁を加えてきた
彼女の中に居座っていれば
If I dwelt within that girl,
I knew that I could punish these
self-proclaimed psychics as well.
くだらない霊能力者どもにも
制裁を加えられる
This is how I chose to use my powers.
それが
私の選んだ“力”の使い方だ
You are allowed to use your
powers for yourself...
“力”は自分のために使っていい
いや 使うべきなんだ
No, you should be using
your powers for yourself.
You understand that now, don't you?
今の君なら 分かるだろう？
Here you go.
（モブ）
ほら
Well, that's a crappy thing to do.
（みのり）
いっけないんだ～
野良猫に餌付けするのは
公共のマナー違反だよね～
Don't you know that feeding strays
is a public disservice?
What are you going to do about that cat?
その猫 どうすんの？
N-Nothing...
（モブ）
ど… どうもしないよ
Really? That poor thing.
何 それ？　かわいそう～
In that case, the cat's
probably better off dying.
だったら 早く死んだほうが
猫も楽かも
I'll go take it to a shelter.
保健所に連れてくね
（モブ）
やめろ　飼う 飼うよ！
Don't... I'll take it in.
I'll take care of it!
Quit scaring Asagiri-san, you punk!
（男子生徒）
てめえ 浅桐さん
怖がらせてんじゃねえよ！
えい！
（男子生徒）ええい！　ええい！
（蹴る音）
The door broke open!
（霊能力者１）
ドアが壊れた？
But it was sealed so tightly...
（霊能力者２）
あんなに固く封じられていたのに！
It worked out because he's not concentrating
as much of his power out here.
ヤツが こっちに割く力を
緩めたおかげで
なんとかなったぜ
Now we can get out.
（霊能力者３）
これで出られるぞ！
（霊能力者たち）
とにかく救急車を呼べ！
負傷者を運び出せ！
Call an ambulance!
Carry out the wounded!
逃げねえのか？
You're not going to run away?
もう茂夫を助けるのは不可能だ
どうして残る？
Shigeo's done for.
Why are you staying behind?
信用してるからだ
Because I trust in him.
In this situation?
Are you really this stupid?
この状況で…
そんなにバカだったのか？
Yup, I am.
ああ　バカだと思うぞ
This is probably the first time someone's
placed so much trust in you too, right?
お前も ここまで他人に
信じてもらえたのは初めてだろ？
Mob trusts us... because he's stupid.
モブは俺たちを信用してるんだ
バカだからな
あいつは まだまだ利用できる
I've still got plenty of use for him,
and considering that,
running away is the last thing I want to do.
そう思ったら
逃げてる場合じゃねえだろ？
ハア～
Well, I can't bring out
Shigeo's latent powers on my own.
（エクボ）
確かに俺様じゃ
茂夫本来のパワーは引き出せねえ
In that case, it'd be more effective
to manipulate him from the shadows.
だったら まだ陰の参謀として
茂夫を利用したほうが効率がいい
I changed my mind. I'll stay behind as well.
気が変わった　俺様も残る
Good. Let's wait this out.
まあ 待とうぜ
（エクボ）
いや 待ってても
茂夫は戻ってこられねえ
Nope. Waiting's not going
to bring Shigeo back.
I guess I'll have to take
care of this myself.
俺様が ひと肌 脱いでやんぜ！
Are you frustrated? Enraged?
（最上）
悔しいか？　怒っているか？
Do you hate them? Do you despise them?
憎んでいるか？　恨んでいるか？
They are a cancer to society.
こいつらは社会のガン
Stop letting them use you.
もう利用される側に立つのは よせ
You will be reborn as my sympathizer.
君は私の理解者として生まれ変わる
I shall give you strength...
“力”を与えよう
Make your negative emotions explode
and use them against the world!
そして 負の感情を
世界に向けて爆発させろ！
（エクボ）
ぐぐっ… ぐぎぎ…
I'm having a hard time getting in...
Shigeo actually got through this shield?
なかなか入れねえ
茂夫のヤツ こんなシールド
突破したのか クソ！
Damn it!
おっ？　なんか霊力 湧いてきたぞ
Hey, I can feel my spiritual power spiking.
This should work!
これなら いけるぜ！
Did it work?
うまくいったのか？
You owe me one.
（魔津尾(まつお)）
貸しにしとくわ
Now that I've helped you,
you'd better win this.
そのかわり 絶対 勝ちなさいよね
Wh-What's with you?
な… なんなの あんた？
I-I can have Papa's bodyguards beat
the crap out of you anytime I want!
か… 影山君なんて
パパのボディーガードに頼めば
ボッコボコよ！
So what?
（モブ）
だから 何？
ひいっ
（モブ）謝れ
（みのり）ええっ？
Apologize.
（最上）
そう　消してしまえ！
Yes... Make her disappear!
Apologize.
謝れ
I-I'm sorry...
ごめんなさい
もし次 僕に構ったら…
If you ever bother me again...
Die, you freak!
（男子生徒）
くたばれ 化け物！
フフ… お前なんか死ねばいい
You should just die.
What did I ever do to you people?
僕があんたらに
何をしたっていうんだ？
I can't think of a single thing...
さっぱり分からない
But it doesn't matter.
でも 分からなくてもいい
どうでもいい
None of this matters.
It's complete. You finally changed.
（最上）
完成だ　やっと変わってくれた
You were a lot like me,
君は私に似ていた
and that's why I didn't want you
to travel the same path I did.
だから 私のような人生を
送ってほしくなかったんだ
（エクボ）
おい！
Hey.
（モブ）
鼻水が しゃべった！
The snot's talking?!
No trespassing
Seasoning Realty
Man, you're pretty far gone, aren't you?
（エクボ）
あ～
これ だいぶ イッちゃってんな
Hey, do you know who I am?
おい 俺様が分かるか？
（モブ）
何だ？　この生き物
What the heck is this creature?
Actually, before that...
っと その前にと… あれか！
There he is.
Quit lurking.
のぞき見んな！
（エクボ）
まやかしなんかに
引っ掛かりやがって！
Damn you for actually falling
for these illusions.
しょうがねえ
Fine.
I'll have to use all the spiritual power
I've stocked up, but...
今までせっかく
霊力を貯金してきたのに…
ショック療法だ！
Time for some shock therapy!
（殴る音）
（モブ）ぶほっ！
Remember, Shigeo.
思い出せ 茂夫！
外で霊幻と待ってんだ！
Reigen and I are waiting for you outside!
Rei... gen? Who's that?
レイゲン？　誰だ？
Oh, hey, Mob. Sorry, but could
you hurry to the office?
（霊幻）
おう モブ
悪(わり)いけど すぐ事務所 来れるか？
A huge job just came in.
デカい仕事が入ってな
Your master needs your help,
so you better hurry it up.
師匠の頼みだ　急げよ
Mas... ter?
師匠？
Stop using your powers for
dumb things in this dumb world.
くだらねえ世界で
くだらねえ力を使うな
Don't you want to be a big brother
your little brother can look up to?
弟に尊敬される兄だろうが
弟… 僕に？
My little brother? Look up to me?
間違えて履いてた！
律(りつ)の靴だ これ
I accidentally wore the wrong
shoes. These are Ritsu's.
（エクボ）
最上ごときの口車に乗るな
Don't let Mogami influence you like that.
You even managed to stick to your values
when you fought Hanazawa!
お前は花沢(はなざわ)にだって
頑固を通してただろ！
That's right...
そうだ　人に使っちゃいけない
“力”だったんだ
I'm not supposed to use these
powers against other people.
大体 凡人相手に簡単に負けんなよ
Not to mention, why are you
losing so easily to commoners?
肉体改造部の名が泣くぞ
You bring shame to the Body Improvement Club!
Where did all those muscles you built up go?
あんなに鍛えた筋肉は
どこ行った！
I don't know how much time
you've spent in this dump,
どんだけ長い時間を
ここで過ごしたかは分からんが―
but this isn't like you.
らしくねえな！
Do you want your beloved
Tsubomi-chan to hate you?
憧れのツボミちゃんに嫌われるぞ！
よくやった
Well done.
（影山 律）兄さん
（テル）やあ！
Nii-san.
Heya.
Body improvement!
（肉体改造部一同）
肉改！　ファイ オー！
Fight on!
（エクボ）
そりゃ 盛り過ぎだろ
Okay, that's going way too far...
I remember.
（モブ）
思い出した
（エクボ）
えっ？
相棒の俺様のことも思い出したか？
Do you remember me, too?
I'm your partner!
No, not really...
いや それはちょっと…
Seriously?
（エクボ）
おい！　なんでだよ？
I'm kidding.
冗談だよ　ありがとう エクボ
Thanks, Dimple.
So what if your memories came back?
（最上）
記憶が戻ったから何だというんだ？
The six months you've spent here
are forever etched into your heart.
ここでの半年間は
君の心深くに刻まれたはずだ
I know you were hearing
my voice subconsciously.
私の声も
無意識下で届いていただろう？
Mogami...
最上
Just like you said, the world can be
a cruel and messed-up place.
（モブ）
あんたの言うとおり 世界は残酷で
間違ってる部分もある
You helped me see it in a new light.
さすがに考えが変わったよ
Huh? Don't tell me you...
（エクボ）
え？　お前 まさか…
I'm truly blessed. I need to be
more thankful to everyone around me
僕は幸せ者だ
もっと周りに感謝しよう
once I get back to the real world.
現実に戻ったらね
So that's how it's going to be?
（最上）
そうなってしまうか
And here I thought I'd found
a sympathizer. How disappointing.
拍子抜けだ
せっかく
理解者になれそうだったのに…
One other thing.
（モブ）
それと もう１つ
People can change through
their interactions with others.
人は人との関わり合いで
変わることができる
I was able to change because of everyone.
みんなのおかげで僕は変わった
I was able to become a little stronger
than if I had been alone.
１人で生きる僕より
少し強い僕になったんだ
If I'm able to change, then everyone
else should be able to as well.
僕が変われたなら
きっと誰でもそうなんだ
That means no one is worthless.
だったら
価値のない人間なんていない
Don't say another word...
（最上）
そこまでにしておけ
地獄を見るぞ
Or you'll have hell to pay.
（モブ）
あんたの創った“僕”が
あんたに負けても 僕は違う
The Shigeo you fabricated might
succumb to you, but I won't.
逃げないよ
I'm not going to run.
I still have that awful Asagiri-san to save.
まだ 最低な浅桐さんを
助けてないんだから
Mob Psycho
A spiritual mutation?
（エクボ）
霊体変異！
Guess we're gonna have to fight!
You up for this, Shigeo?
腹くくるしかねえ！
茂夫 やれんのか？
Looks like there's nothing to worry about.
心配なさそうだな
あっ！　ほかにもいるぞ！
Here come more of them!
この世界の住人全てが…
Every inhabitant of this world is...
Shigeo!
（エクボ）
茂夫！
That's...
これは…
I'm going to defeat this evil
spirit and go back to reality.
（モブ）
悪霊を退治して 現実に帰るんだ！
And what good would that do?
（最上）
帰ってどうする？
The life you lead won't change,
and nor will society's absurdities.
同じような日々 不合理な社会
There will be plenty of things
to annoy and trouble you.
いらだって
煩わしいことも たくさん起きる
The outside world is... scary?
（モブ）
外が怖い？
Life is frustrating, devoid of meaning,
and so, so painful.
（最上）
悔しい むなしい
生きるのは苦しいもんだ
I can hear them...
（モブ）
聞こえてくる　亡者たちの声が
The voices of the dead
are speaking to me.
伝わってくる　多くの悲鳴が
So many screams...
They died feeling like this?
こんな気持ちで死んでいったのか
Is this how they felt when they were alive?
こんな気持ちで生きていたのか
It's such a cruel world...
こんな過酷な世界に…
Am I really going to be able to...
僕は本当に…
...me...
（声）
…けて
（モブ）
この声…
That voice!
（声）
助けて
Help me...
（モブ）
ああ そうだった
Oh... That's right.
I came here to save someone.
僕は人を助けに来たんだった
I always thought these powers
were of no use to anybody,
何ひとつ 人の役に立たないと
思ってたこの“力”で
人を生かすんだ！
but I'll use them to save people!
今更 何をしても 私には勝てんぞ！
It doesn't matter what you do.
You cannot defeat me!
Shigeo... you did it.
（エクボ）
茂夫 やったな さすが
Well, I'll be damned.
（最上）
さっきまでの少年じゃない
You're not the same boy from earlier.
Who are you?
お前 誰だ？
やっと こいつの怖さが
分かったか？
You finally get how freaky he is?
This is Kageyama Shigeo's true form
that he reveals when he's pissed—
これが 影山茂夫が
ブチ切れたときに見せる真の姿…
Dimple.
（モブ）
エクボ
It's dangerous, so leave
this to me and stay back.
危ないから　僕に任せて離れていて
Actually, yeah, who are you?
（エクボ）
ホントに 誰だよ？
（ナレーション）
最上は見落としていた
Mogami had overlooked something
that lay dormant within Mob.
モブの中に眠っていた意気
A person's heart is made up
of two sides of the same coin.
人の心は表裏一体
Just as happiness shines
in the shadows of sorrow,
悲しみがあるから喜びがあるように
only in the darkest depths of fear
それは 強い恐怖と対(つい)を成す勇気
does courage truly shine.
The powerful blast from
Mob's positive emotions at 100%
（ナレーション）
正の感情が100パーセント表出した
モブの強烈な一撃により
annihilated the great evil spirit, Mogami.
大悪霊 最上は完全に消滅
Or at least, that's how it looked.
…したかに思えた
Now that they've lost me, their vessel,
（最上）
私という器が壊れたことで
all of the evil spirits that I'd taken in
and controlled will all be freed at once.
これまで
取り込んで制御していた悪霊は
一斉に解き放たれる
Not even I can stop them anymore.
もう私自身の手に負えなくなる
（エクボ）
茂夫！
Shigeo!
Dimple, go ahead and head back!
エクボ 先に戻れ！
僕は大丈夫だから！
I'll be fine!
Y-You sure about that?!
だ… 大丈夫って お前
I'm going to save Asagiri-san.
（モブ）
僕は浅桐さんを助ける！
I'm going to completely exorcise
them before I leave.
確実に除霊してから脱出する
I'll be back, I promise.
必ず帰るから 心配するな
Don't worry.
ヘッ 俺様も食う気か？
You trying to eat me, too?
Damn it. Catch me if you can, you bastards!
チクショー
捕まえてみろ この野郎 上等だ！
Bring it!
I'll be waiting for you on the other side!
待ってるぜ～！
In this world,
（モブ）
この世界 目に入るもの全部が霊体
everything I can see is a spirit.
I have to exorcise them all.
全部 除霊しないと！
No matter how much you struggle,
（最上）
君が どうあがいても
向かう先は私と同じく破滅だ
your path will lead you to
the same place mine did...
To ruin.
I'm going to save her... I...
助けるんだ 僕は…
I can't go out like this!
こんな所で…
（最上）
そうか
君という器が壊れたことで…
I see.
Your vessel has been shattered,
and that's what is inside?
中身が それか
I actually thought you might've died.
死んだかと思ったぜ
That took you ages.
結構 長かったな
Yes, a very long time...
はい　とても
Master, how's Asagiri-san?
師匠 浅桐さんは？
Well, if you're awake...
（霊幻）
お前が起きたってことは…
He's still—
（モブ）
まだ… あっ！
You've made your choice.
（最上）
君は選択をした
I'll keep watching from afar to see
if you made the right one.
その生き方が正しいかどうか
遠くから見ているよ
（魔津尾）
まだ消えるのは早いわよ
You're not going anywhere, my pet.
That was an unexpected trophy. Thank you.
思わぬ収穫だったわ　ありがとう
Isn't that... I didn't even
realize he was here.
（霊幻）
あいつは！
全然 気付かなかった
I'll make sure I take
really good care of him.
（魔津尾）
じっくり大切に育ててあげるわ
Farewell. Perhaps we'll see each other again.
それじゃ またどこかで
Kageyama-kun?
影山君？
Yeah.
What? You guys know each other?
（霊幻）
なんだ 知り合いだったのか？
Nah, she probably just remembers
what happened over there.
（エクボ）
いや 向こうでの出来事が
記憶されてんだな
Are you really always like that?
君は本当に あんな感じなの？
Yeah... I am.
あんな感じ　ごめんね
I'm sorry.
I'm really... really sorry...
本当に… ごめんなさい
I'm so sorry! I'm so sorry!
ごめんなさい　ごめんなさい
（モブ）
いいんだ　もう分かったから
It's okay. I understand.
何が？
Understand what?
人は変われるってこと
That people can change.
Mogami-san and Asagiri-san
taught me that.
最上さんと浅桐さんが
教えてくれたんだ
The people around me changed me as well.
僕もみんなに変えてもらった
Now I know that I might
be able to change others too,
僕も誰かを変えられる
かもしれないって分かったから
こうやって…
so I'm glad we were able to meet.
会えてよかったよ
Thank you...
ありがとう
（浅桐正志(まさし)）
みのりを救ったのは
同級生の男子だと言ったな
So you're saying the one who
saved you is a boy in your grade?
Yeah, why?
それがどうしたの？
依頼した中に
中学生なんていないんだ
There wasn't a middle school student
among the people I hired.
Huh?
He wasn't even asked to be there,
頼んでもいないのに
but he managed to exorcise an evil
spirit that no one else could
誰も退治できなかった悪霊を
除霊して
and left without saying a word.
名乗らずに去っていった
That's so cool.
かっこいいね
またいつか会いたいな
I hope I can see him again.
いろいろ調べてみたら―
I did a bit of research,
and this caught my eye.
１つ引っ掛かる結果が出た
Psycho Helmet Religion
Huh? Isn't that...
（みのり）
あれ？　これって…
（信者１）
教団の収入源が
寄付だけじゃ―
Our religious organization is not
going to survive on donations alone.
維持できないな
It's going to be impossible
to build a headquarters.
（信者２）
これじゃ本部を作るなんて
不可能だ
Not to mention our beloved founder
is still nowhere to be found.
（信者３）
いつまでたっても
教祖様は消息不明だし
Ow.
Current Balance:
（信者４）あ～あ
（パソコンの着信音）
Thank you for your continued business with us.
There has been a deposit of 500,000,000 JPY to your account.
Thank you
Current available balance: 500,010,180 JPY
Master, why aren't you
going to claim your reward?
（モブ）
師匠
なんで報酬をもらいに
行かないんですか？
Look how many people got hurt.
あんなに
ケガ人が出たんだ
I wouldn't exactly call that a success.
成功とは言えんだろ
You should never accept money
you feel you haven't earned.
微妙な金は
受け取らねえほうがマシだ
If you do, you'll start to
always take the easy way out.
でないと 今後も
楽な方向に流れていくだろ
You just don't want to be held responsible.
（エクボ）
責任追及されんのが
怖(こえ)えんだろ？
That's not it, you moron!
違(ちげ)えよ バカ！
Anyway, no good ever comes out
of drowning in wealth or power.
まあ 金でも権力でも
力に溺れると
ろくでもないことになっていくんだ
Mogami let his own powers
swallow him up, too.
最上も自分の能力に
のまれたってことだな
You know...
お前もさ
有名になったり偉くなるよりは
You're better off working part-time for me
than becoming famous or powerful.
俺の手伝いで
バイトやってるくらいが―
ちょうどいいバランスなんだよ
Oh, give me a friggin' break...
また勝手なこと
言ってやがる
（吸引音）
（モブ）ぷはっ！
Hey, quit clowning around with your
classmates, Mob! We're busy here.
（霊幻）
おい このクソ忙しいときに
同級生と戯れてんじゃねえよ モブ
They're just using you!
そいつら
お前を利用してるだけなんだぞ！
Jeez. You never learn, do you?
ったく 成長しねえな お前はよ
次回「モブサイコ100 Ⅱ」
Next time on Mob Psycho 100 II Episode 6:
第６話
“孤独なホワイティー”
"Poor, Lonely, Whitey."
Poor, Lonely, Whitey
The DVDs? That's an excellent decision!
ＤＶＤ？　とても正しい判断です